thescene.com 2011-04-28

# Privacy Policy - The Scene

Last updated: January 1st 2011

Protecting the privacy of all of our users is a dedicated commitment of thescene.com and all of the services brought to you by thescene.com (collectively, "The Scene", 'us' or 'we'). This Privacy Policy ('Privacy Policy'), applies to all URLs and services provided under the The Scene name and in connection with the The Scene marks. It explains how The Scene treats personal information that we collect and receive on the The Scene website from our users and visitors.

Personal information is information about you that is not otherwise available to the public. As the words imply, this information personally identifies you. Personal information may include, but is not limited to, your name, location, e-mail address, birth date, or other identifying information.

You should be aware that this Privacy Policy applies ONLY to the The Scene website, the The Scene URLs, and the services and features provided by The Scene. This Privacy Policy does not apply to websites that you visit before or after us, to the other third party services featured on the The Scene site, or to third party advertisers or affiliates (collectively, 'Third Party Services'). Please be sure to familiarize yourself with all of these Third Party Services' privacy policies.

Now that you know what this Privacy Policy covers, you may have the following questions:

**WHAT INFORMATION DOES The Scene COLLECT?**

First and foremost, we DO NOT intentionally collect information from children or adults under the age of 21. We realize that the reach of theBarBook may be broad and we have taken steps to ensure the safety of our users or visitors.

**General User Registration:** When you register to become a general member of a theBarBook, we collect certain information about you. This information is your desired username, e-mail address, country and gender (collectively, "General Membership Information"). Once registered, you will have the opportunity to create your personal profile. ANY PERSONAL INFORMATION ABOUT YOURSELF THAT YOU DO NOT WISH TO SHARE WITH THE PUBLIC SHOULD NOT BE INCLUDED ON YOUR PERSONAL PROFILE.

**Non-Personally Identifiable Information:** The Scene also collects non-personally identifiable information about you. Currently, upon registration, The Scene only collects your IP address, which cannot personally identify you. The Scene also complies user data in the aggregate for purposes of demographic compilations and other data that can help us enhance our user's experience.

**The Scene Community Features:** Once you register for The Scene, you will also have a chance, at your sole determination, to share other information about yourself via your personal profile. This information will be included on your personal The Scene profile and is meant for sharing with other community members of The Scene. You will always have the ability to change and edit this information. Further information on this is provided below.

NOTE: Please remember that any personal information voluntarily disclosed by you through e-mail, in public-view personal profiles, public-view uploaded materials, chat rooms, message boards, or intra-site message systems, can be seen and used by others. For your safety, do not include information on your personal profile that you do not want others to know!

**WHAT IS COLLECTING THE ABOVE INFORMATION?**

**Cookies:** The Scene places cookies on your computer to retain your individual preferences and improve your user experience on our website, as well as to tell us what features of our sites are most popular. From time to time, we randomly track what our users are viewing / searching for via client-side cookies. We do this through a randomly generated username only and cannot tie this to your personal data. So in short, we do not store any personal information in cookies, nor do we use cookies to obtain any personal information from you. You can always adjust your web browser's acceptance of cookies in your browser preferences.

Also, affiliates and advertisers, product and service providers may also use their own cookies when you interact with their sites via The Scene. You should be aware of this and always consult with their privacy policies.

**Our Database:** All of the General Membership Information Information is stored in our database. The Scene does not use external, file-based or xml storage devises.

**HOW DO WE USE MEMBERSHIP INFORMATION AND NON-PERSONALLY IDENTIFIABLE INFORMATION?**

General Membership Information: The Scene will not distribute, sell or rent any of the personal information about you to other people or nonaffiliated companies except to enable the provision of services or products you have requested or when we have your permission to do so.

Our advertisers will never be privy to your General Membership Information unless you permit us to give it to them so that they can provide you with products or services.

Your e-mail address may be used by us for communications related to the The Scene services, including but not limited to, sending notices about new features, products, or other information of interest to you. Again, you can always opt-out of receiving these notices.

Non-Personally Identifiable Information: Our advertisers and affiliates may be provided general information or data regarding member usage patterns or interests, or other general demographic information so that they can better serve your needs and preferences. However, such disclosure will not include individually identifiable information. The collection of usage and interest information allows us to provide a constantly evolving innovative services, products, and features designed to satisfy member needs, wants and desires.

**WHEN WILL WE SHARE OR DISCLOSE GENERAL MEMBERSHIP INFORMATION?**

Despite our commitment to protecting your privacy, in certain circumstances, The Scene may disclose your General Membership Information under the following circumstances:

> (a) If required to do so by law;
> 
> (b) Pursuant to a good faith belief that such access, preservation or disclosure is reasonably necessary to:
> 
> 1) Enforce the The Scene Terms of Service;  
>  2) Respond to claims that any uploaded materials violate the rights of third-parties;  
>  3) Respond to your customer service requests;  
>  4) Comply with legal process; and/or  
>  5) Protect the rights, property, or personal safety of The Scene, its users, or the public.

**HOW DO I EDIT MY MEMBERSHIP INFORMATION?**

All of your General Membership Information is located in your personal The Scene account. Your profile can be edited at any time, by logging in with your username and password, then clicking on the "Edit Profile" link on the top-right of the page. In addition, within all communications send to you from us at The Scene, we will always provide you with instructions for opting out from additional communication.

**HOW DOES The Scene PROTECT MY INFORMATION? (SECURITY)**

Your personal account is protected by your password, which you select. The Scene uses commercially reasonable efforts to protect our user data and restricts our employees access to such data, except to those whose primary job function it is to maintain this data. Please note that apart from the commercially reasonable efforts we employ, due to conditions beyond our control, we cannot guarantee 100% security of user personal data.

**WHAT ABOUT SAFETY FOR CHILDREN?**

Again, we at The Scene take the online safety of children very seriously. We do our best not to allow users under the age of 21 in general to obtain a an account on The Scene. 

**I AM AN INTERNATIONAL USER, WHAT ABOUT MY PRIVACY?**

The Scene treats everyone the same. The Scene is owned and operated in the United States of America and our servers are located in the United States of America. Therefore, the collection of user data is governed, to the extent they exist, by United States federal and state privacy law.

**WHAT IF The Scene MAKES CHANGES TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY?**

The Scene may periodically update this Privacy Policy. We will attempt, at our sole discretion, to notify our users of any updates to this Privacy Policy via email. However, we encourage you to periodically revisit the Privacy Policy link on the The Scene homepage to ensure that you are familiar with the current version. You are responsible for reviewing any revisions to this Privacy Policy, and your continued use of the The Scene website and services after any change to the policy constitutes your acceptance of the Privacy Policy.

**CAN I CONTACT The Scene ABOUT MY PRIVACY CONCERNS / QUESTIONS?**

Yes! If you have a privacy concern regarding the The Scene website or this Privacy Policy feel free to write us at [privacy@thescene.com](mailto:privacy@thescene.com).
